Srinadh Somboju — Microsoft certified Python Developer at TCS.

Contact Info: Mobile No +91 9137477260 Email Id: sombojusrinadh@gmail.com

Total Experience in IT Industry: 6 Years

Career Summary

Strong collaboration and team building skills with proficiency at grasping new technical concepts quickly and utilize the same in a productive manner. Excellent communication skills, positive attitude towards team working, willingness to learn new technologies and working on a mission to be a data scientist in near future.

On-site: Have been to Client Location for 6 months for VAT development, implementation and provided them solutions based on live case scenarios.

April 2019 - Present (2.4 years) and Project: Nordea

Nordea is a bank. It is the largest financial group and is the result of the successive mergers and acquisitions of Finnish, Danish Norwegian and Swedish banks of merita Bank. Currently am undertaking the complete responsibility of the module Teller Application.

Roles & Responsibilities: FullStack development of Understanding the BRD Requirements, Functional Implementation, code development, Implementation, Unit Testing. Involved and developed the complex API's using REST services.

Technologies: Python, PL/SQL, NumPy, AWS, Rest services, cloud, Pyspark, Pandas, JavaScript, spark, html5, Shell Scripting, MySql

Frameworks: Django,

DB & Other tools and Servers: Oracle, PostgresSQL, GitHub, Jenkins, Ninjago, Bitbucket, Microservices, Tortoise SVN, Apache HTTP server, IBoss.

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Awards: "On the Spoc" award for grasping and adapting to the project circumstances and for taking solely the project accountability.

July 2015 - Feb 2019 (3.7 years) at Infrasoft Technologies Ltd

Involved in the development of Banking and Financial products like Loan Origination System, CBS etc. Efficiently converted Business requirements into Enterprise Solutions with cooperation of Team Leads and Business Analysts.

Awards: Awarded with the "star of the month" recognition for my services for the successful implementation of VAT.

Projects

(LOS) Loan Origination System

Feb 2016 to Feb 2019

Loan Origination solution assists a financial enterprise to manage the entire loan origination workflow starting with on-boarding through application, appraisal and approval processes.

Technologies used: Python, Core Java, Struts2, JavaScript, hibernate, JSF, Apache Tomcat, JSP, Eclipse-Link, JQuery, SQL

Roles & Responsibilities: Understanding the BRD Requirements, Functional Implementation, developing Code , implementing and doing the

unit testing.

Role: Full Stack Development and Involved Specially in CEP(Complex Event Processing)

Technologies Used : Core Java, Struts2, hibernate, Apache Tomcat, JSP, Eclipse-Link, JavaScript, SQL

Skills and Expertise:

Programming Languages- Python3,SQL,PL/SQL, Java	Web Frameworks- Django,Struts2, ApacheStorm,
Scripting- JavaScript, jQuery,	ORM Frameworks- Hibernate
Relational Databases- Oracle, MS-SQL,Postgressql	Others- CSS, Jquery, TIPCO, Xhtml, servlets, jsp
IDE- Pycharm, Atom, JBoss Developer, Eclipse, IDEA	Web/Application Server- Tomcat, JBoss, Microservices.

Education

MLR Institute of Technology, Hyderbad

70.2% in B.Tech in 2011-2015 batch

Sri Chaitanya Junior College, Hyderabad percent: 93% in Hyderabad (2009 – 2011)

Little Flower School, Hyderabad

Grade: 87.8 % in SSC (2009)

Certifications

$\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Major project paper publishment on Motion Controlled Semi-Humanoid ROBOT} \\ \textbf{IJRASET} \end{tabular}$

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 18 Jan 1995

Hobbies: Cooking, Playing chess, Exploring New Places and People, Solving Puzzles **Current Address:** H No:2-1-22/6, sai prashanth Nagar, Kukatpally, Hyderabad

Mobile Number: +91-7207297030,9137477260

I hereby declare that the information provided by is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: **Hyderabad** Srinadh Somboju.